Well, caught over the regular meeting of my
city council for Monday, August 21st, 2023.
And this was a meeting you showed up for, Mr. Sheth.
Hi.
Two public inputer and let's get a little personal
appearances.
Men.
Three claims.
Thank you.
All right.
Three.
Five.
Williams.
Parker.
Five.
Five presentation from Grand Gateway, Pelvan.
Mr. Kinder McGeeady.
And Aaron Clapper.
Hello, Ian.
Hello.
Hi.
Well, we can't have a week to go.
In this is a few five.
And it gives you updates about Pelvan.
Transmission.
There were a couple more questions that you had to be answered.
So we wanted to come back and give you that opportunity tonight.
We were told that you wanted us to come back tonight.
So we're here.
I just need to go a little update if you want.
So in the last couple of weeks, the services have been going great.
So we're getting ready to implement the new technology very soon.
And we've done a rebrand with our vehicles.
We're going to do some of those running around.
Your members are holding steady.
And right now we are looking at trips.
About a hundred and fifty more a month.
And we're doing this time.
So we're really excited about that.
But I want to make sure that we have.
How many people do you pick up in the city?
Well, let's see.
I could just tell you exactly how many registered users we have in this city of
Miami.
But I can tell you that we do around 40 trips today.
And we just hired a new driver for Miami.
How many drivers do you have?
Right now we have four.
Now we have five.
We have one.
We just came in and finished that.
The orientation is in today.
And we'll be on the road next week.
Do you have an office in Miami more?
No, we don't.
As I updated that was we had an office here for several years.
And when I took over we didn't have an office.
That was part of the tribe.
The Miami tribe gave us that office space as part.
As you know, we run an operation for them as well.
And at some point shortly after COVID,
the tribe folded to another tribe.
I'm also located here in Ottawa County.
We've decided to do some remodel in a kind of shelter with that office.
And so, they decided to do something different with the building, so we do not have an office space here, and haven't had one for about two years.
Do you guys plan to get in another one?
Yep, we do not.
We are, we have a mobility management center in Big cabin.
We dispatch our entire operation with Big cabin.
We're also a designated regional and building management center for ODOT.
So, this is kind of part of the Big statewide plan.
Again, with the technology as well, which is on demand, which will probably decrease in the cost of cost center.
But no, we do not have to have this space here in my oven.
Yeah, that's pretty weird.
You still do not have to.
I guess one missed out last meeting, but when you mentioned the new technology, what is that, just a $10,000 book?
Well, it's basically like over the, we have our own app.
It's a pelvican app, so riders will be able to book correctly and spontaneously, like on demand within, I think, our server level will be about 10 minutes.
That's a big cool app.
You rotate, just a few.
So, we basically have, we'll still have a call center, because we understand in rural transit.
There are different things that we want to do, you don't have access to smart phones or broadband.
So, we want to make sure that we cover all the bases when it comes to cooking options.
We're doing the graphics.
Since COVID, the younger generation, they don't drive.
They don't feel a lot of things that we do.
But the driving is one of them.
The technology, since they're their style.
I have 15 year old, you can know that.
How much money do you guys get usually in a year with the tribes and us all together?
Can you tell us that?
Um, I don't know what year.
Well, the tribal operation is, uh, the short answer is now.
Uh, I can't tell you an exact amount.
The tribal operation, and I keep in mind I have been out of finding it.
It's a part of the effort I was not to.
So the sixth reel.
The fifth, the third, 11 grant. How much is it?
11 grant. Well, it's, even mine, our 53, 11 grant is for the entire seven kind of region.
Uh, I, I, I, if you want to know what we spend on the land, uh, operation.
Separate the tribe.
It's probably around 300,000.
Your matches, 48, I believe.
You're still spending that much, even though you don't have an office here in the town.
So how?
The gasoline is going to be absolutely, absolutely.
I'm sorry.
I'm not making that.
Are you not making that up and the costs of the rise?
Yeah.
Probably transit.
We don't have money.
We get $3 per.
It's a, it's a service that the heart is what public transit is.
Try to break even.
That's, that's a good year for a very sensitive operation.
How big varied, yes, cover?
$4,466 square miles.
So again, $466.
How many of that's my own?
I know what your debt service area is.
I'm going to say $667.
Do it by 200 now.
All right.
I don't know what you're, I don't know what you're,
what you're exactly on the answer you're.
Is that what Ferris, $3?
No.
Where is every senior citizen just wanted it?
It seems as if it's wanting it.
A lot of people will be providing services to live on this.
But the county county.
$422.
So is that what the this area covers the district county?
Well, yeah, I mean, we cover Ottawa, Craig,
Delaware, Mays.
We cover the entire apartment.
Well, I'm at with the 306, is it just the 482 for our county?
Yes, yes.
It's 48.
It's 46.
How many riders do you guys have?
And, no, because you get 40 a day here, how many do you get a day
over in, say, Craig County?
I don't know.
It just depends on the number of drivers.
We give about $150,000 from the area throughout our tire operations.
Your spent at $21 a ride, you take me in three or $1.
I'm going to buy that.
Is that good, too?
Yeah, man.
Jill, have we got it before?
Or is that, you know?
It was a plus meaning, not this meaning, but that.
Well, I was looking at it.
Well, to be honest, I really kind of want to know why we're spending so much money when we only pick up 40 people a day.
I'm not trying to be rude or anything, but I'm just trying to figure out why we're taking the city's money and spending so much money of the city's money.
When we're only picking up approximately 40 people a day.
Well, you know, $46,000 is a premium match to a $300,000 operation.
So I have to kind of say that because it is very expensive to run.
But, you know, if this is a service that you guys feel like your pain's might still weaken, you know, talk about this itself.
Well, you know, I mean, we got a lot of things that we need to do in the city a lot, like the roads.
So you guys can drive on them.
So that was my question.
I wondered why we've been in so much money with 40 people a day.
Those people are going to work.
That's one thing.
I would like that in consideration.
A lot of people are going to work.
So again, understand?
Do you track that?
Yeah.
I'm a little bit, yes, you've done it for me.
Can you kind of start?
55, and they have.
So you said the drives out was how I was doing.
I think how long I, yeah.
sure you all know where I think I mentioned I'm working on it for seven day a week service
service and you know the questions thank you yes I'll get you remember I was
saying yeah if you will send us a citizen you know we want to make sure everything
you need thank you thank you both six joint resolution MSU-823-08-C-2023-11
for each meeting you find so support and free waiver to an organic home for demolition
structures and removal various degrees within the city limits of my home
this one Christy talked about earlier
second
five
fiscal year 2022 assistance to five five
grant the amount of twenty six thousand thirty six dollars and ninety nine cents
five
I'd like to motion to approve.
Thank you.
Parker?
Aye.
Senator?
Thank you.
Eight vote on recommendation for the city's zoning and planning commission to
rezone a lot.
17 and 18 block 100 and a city of Miami.
Residents of multi-family to general commercial.
The pre-war that's 2023 that's 0.7.
Mending the zoning map.
I was Jones and Mr. Chestnut.
As you all know, you know where the county garage was.
The number you've been.
Did you say you had someone that?
Right.
As a bright now.
That was like a resident in there.
How many of the city have you asked?
I think what happened was.
Sure.
Dean took over some cars that had been up for something like the top.
And they didn't really cover those in the room.
So it wouldn't be there anymore.
I think their attention really now is just to clear the vehicles and get back on the road.
So they are in demolished.
They're building them in there.
So take it down.
They're ready.
They really don't want to see you.
But they're in a good privacy.
Just behind the case of the car.
Make sure that it doesn't make it make it make a motion we approve
Second
Hi
I think we're going in
I don't think we're going to go
Hi Parker
Hi
I think we're going to have that
Thank you yes
Thank you
Thank you for your patience
No
I'm just going to discuss it on upcoming town hall meeting regarding crime
and on the county
I think we're just looking at the council
that we have been invited to a town hall meeting
It's sponsored by
I don't care if welcome and don't care part of both
Another point is all that has a law enforcement for county
With confirmations for the chairman of the sheriff
The district attorney's office all
And then to confirm any more
And I think it's just a citizen's group that concerned
Overcry and not sure exactly what they're going to ask
But it was one of the council where we are doing a different service center
On the 7th
7th
I have to be there as well. Not to be on any panel or anything, but just be in attendance.
I was on an ask.
I would say that anyone in the council members that want to attend may, but we need to let Melissa know.
I'm going to give you a really just jump in the beta and spare back in a minute.
Thank you.
Ten.
The point Mark Jordan to the MIMA community, facilities authority MCFA, replacing Dr. Mark folks and
service officio.
What is the MCFA?
It's over the state.
Okay.
So, the city has two, which is, myself, a chance to do on the college has two, which is Dr.
Stafford, and that's the Grover, and then the high school has two, which is Nick Heismiff,
and now Mark Jordan.
And then, there's the next one.
Okay.
Oh, man.
We've got a bunch of service at that large.
We're going to pose there and bins there.
I guess about it.
All right.
But it's over the state.
Motion.
Okay.
Perfect.
Williams.
Guy.
He said.
This is my point of bin.
No.
Okay.
You actually choose some probably you ought to know.
I'm staying.
Yeah.
11.
How's the new business of any of which is residents that's posting this agenda?
12 staff reports.
13 mayor counsel for community announcements.
You usually do it, go ahead.
That's real quick.
And I'm going to give a shout out to Brian's neighborhood.
They got together and helped clean up the park.
Cross Street there in Rockville area.
And it was good to see some citizens get out there.
And our guys have been really busy.
They wouldn't want to do it.
It's just they had a lot going on.
They didn't work in the festival.
But some citizens got out there and did some weed eating.
Some edging and stuff.
Brian joined him.
His board.
So I appreciate those guys doing that.
I would like to add to that.
They just did it because they saw that they needed them.
There was no griping or complaining or nobody came to me and said, let's form a committee.
We just.
Everybody grabbed their stuff and saw something and we all just went to town.
And I was there for maybe 10 30 minutes.
But it was, it was pretty cool to see people just go out and do something.
Because it needed to be done.
And it looks.
Let's bear now.
And nobody.
Nobody got hurt.
14, city manager communications. I'd like to recognize three of our firemen that
are now certified as swift water rescue technicians. This is don't-shin Daniel Allen
and Lloyd Johnston. They have the highest level of swift water rescue training offered
to the ocean fire and service training. Myema is obviously no stranger to high water events
so it's extremely important. We have these certified individuals working for us. So I just
wanted to shout out to those guys. Great job. Chief Chenoweth under your leadership. This
is a big opportunity you were able to take advantage of and succeed on. So congratulations
to you and the team. Adding these certifications. Good question. Do we have a new system
party? Yes. We do. Can they? Sure. We can have some of these already Monday.
Sure. Sharon Biggs will be starting Monday as our biggest assistant party. So congratulations
to you. They did a great job in their evaluations, did a search, had a field to evaluate.
He came out as a clear leader. So thank you. Congratulations.